Riccardo Colella

Munich, DE | riccardo_colella@outlook.com | +39 333 349 02 45 | riccardocolella.it https://www.linkedin.com/in/riccardo-colella/ | github.com/RiccardoColella

Overview

I am a Computer Scientist and Engineer, born in Milan but I also lived in Stockholm and Munich. I discovered my love for software engineering and currently I mainly work with containers. I have a strong passion for writing **high-quality code**, I enjoy **learning** new skills, I want to **contribute** my experience to projects and face **challenges** that help me and my team **grow**. I want to **deliver value** from the first day.

Experience

DevOps Engineer, Brainloop AG – Munich, DE

May 2023 – Today

- Saved € 30k/year implementing a Python k8s operator to comply to market specific regulations
- Saved 12+ hr/mo automatizing procedures with **Python** and **shell** scripts
- Reduced data delay in **Elasticsearch** from 2+ hours to few seconds optimizing data processing
- Improved observability of the systems implementing Prometheus rules and Grafana dashboards

Site Reliability Engineer, Amadeus – Erding, DE

Oct 2021 - May 2023

- Set up monitoring and alerting for different middlewares, using Prometheus and Splunk and Grafana
- Responsibility for the Secret Management solution, I've updated and restructured it and its CI/CD pipeline.
- Developed e2e automation of new clusters creation on Azure with Terraform and ArgoCD through IaC
- Developed internal C++ security libraries using TDD and Pair Programming
- Contributed to the **Go** Open Source project External Secrets Operator

Data Scientist, Telenor SE – Stockholm, SE

Jan 2021 – Jun 2021

• Developed a trouble ticket resolution time estimation model capable of *achieving an RMSE of 60 minutes* by a deep study of company procedures and using **ML regressors**.

Education

Politecnico di Milano - Milan, Italy

Oct 2019 - Jul 2021

• Master of Science, Computer Science & Engineering

KTH Royal Institute of Technology - Stockholm, Sweden

Oct 2019 - Jun 2021

• Master of Science, ICT Innovation

Tallin Institute of Technology - Tallin, Estonia

Aug 2020

• Summer School, Innovation & Entrepreneurship

Politecnico di Milano - Milan, Italy

Oct 2016 – Jul 2019

• Bachelor of Science, Computer Science & Engineering

Other

Projects: for a list of projects I have worked on, please visit riccardocolella.it

Programming Languages: Python, Java, C, JavaScript, Go

Technologies: Kubernetes, Docker, Jenkins, Elasticsearch, Azure, Prometheus, Grafana, Helm, ArgoCD/FluxCD,

Terraform, Cyberark, Git

Languages: Italian (C2), English (C2), German (B2)